<oai:record xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <oai:header>
    <oai:identifier>ivo://ia2.inaf.it/edu/inaf_oats/svas/C14/siap</oai:identifier>
    <oai:datestamp>2016-02-05T14:51:01Z</oai:datestamp>
    <oai:setSpec>ivo_managed</oai:setSpec>
  </oai:header>
  <oai:metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">INAF-OATs SVAS Educational Images SIAP service</dc:title>
      <dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">IA2</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">educational galaxies stars planets</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">INAF-OATs SVAS Educational Images SIAP service. Le Stelle Vanno A Scuola (SVAS) proposes a modern tool to support teaching of astronomy, through the study and experimentation of its observation methods. SVAS offers to schools and teachers a remote laboratory with which carry out real observation sessions, managed in real time by the students under the supervision of the teacher, in the classroom, and of an astronomer, at the OATs, thanks to the telematic link between the school and the observatory. Students and teachers experience real astronomical observations, through the interactive participation to the different steps of planning, observing and acquiring the data. The project is addressed to 13-18 yr students. Every observation is previously planned together with the teachers, according to age and curriculum of the students, with the aim to maximize the results. The observing activity, lasting about 90 minutes and led by an astronomer of the OATs, can be done during the morning (observation of the Sun) or in the evening (observation of stars, nebulae, clusters and galaxies). SVAS involves the Astronomical Observatory of Trieste (OATs), the school (of every level) and the University of Trieste. SVAS is supported by the Consorzio per l&#226;&#128;&#153;Incremento degli Studi e delle Ricerche dei Dipartimenti di Fisica e Astronomia dell&#226;&#128;&#153;Universit&#195;&#160; di Trieste and by the Ministero dell'Istruzione, dell'Universit&#195;&#160; e della Ricerca.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">IA2</dc:publisher>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Education</dc:type>
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">ivo://ia2.inaf.it/edu/inaf_oats/svas/C14/siap</dc:identifier>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </oai:metadata>
</oai:record>
