<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:materialscloud.org:2019.0001/v1</identifier>
    <datestamp>2019-06-12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>DOI</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/dc/terms/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:type>Dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:creator>Simoncelli, Michele</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marzari, Nicola</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Mauri, Francesco</dc:creator>
      <dc:title>Unified theory of thermal transport in crystals and disordered solids</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>Materials Cloud</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2019-01-08</dc:date>
      <dc:rights>Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial 4.0 International https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>info:eu-repo/semantics/openAccess</dc:rights>
      <dc:subject>Thermal conductivity</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>CsPbBr3</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Phonon linewidths</dc:subject>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.24435/materialscloud:2019.0001/v1</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>https://archive.materialscloud.org/2019.0001/v1</dc:identifier>
      <dc:language>en</dc:language>
      <dc:description>Crystals and glasses exhibit fundamentally different heat conduction mechanisms: the periodicity of crystals allows for the excitation of propagating vibrational waves that carry heat, as first discussed by Peierls; in glasses, the lack of periodicity breaks Peierls&amp;#39; picture and heat is mainly carried by the coupling of vibrational modes, often described by a harmonic theory introduced by Allen and Feldman. Anharmonicity or disorder are thus the limiting factors for thermal conductivity in crystals or glasses; hitherto, no transport equation has been able to account for both. In the paper https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.01964, we derive such equation, resulting in a thermal conductivity that reduces to the Peierls and Allen-Feldman limits, respectively, in anharmonic-and-ordered or harmonic-and-disordered solids, while also covering the intermediate regimes where both effects are relevant. This approach also solves the long-standing problem of accurately predicting the thermal properties of crystals with ultralow or glass-like thermal conductivity, as we show with an application to a thermoelectric material representative of this class. This database contains the raw data related to the images reported in the paper  https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.01964.</dc:description>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
