<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:oai.datacite.org:9832371</identifier>
    <datestamp>2019-05-31T14:02:40Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>ESTDOI</setSpec>
    <setSpec>ESTDOI.KEEL</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en">Estonian gap tests</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Tkachenko, Alexander</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Center of Estonian Language Resources</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
      <dc:date>Issued: 2016-11-30</dc:date>
      <dc:date>Updated: 2016-12-01</dc:date>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.15155/1-00-0000-0000-0000-00125L</dc:identifier>
      <dc:description>Abstract</dc:description>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en">Estonian gap tests corpus represents a collection of sentences, in which one word is marked as a "gap", accompanied with a list of candidate words. The corpus can be used as a benchmark for evaluating language models. The corpus covers both frequent and infrequent gap-words and includes candidate lists generated in different ways. Sentences originate from the Estonian Reference Corpus (http://www.cl.ut.ee/korpused/segakorpus/). The corpus has been tokenized using Estnltk toolkit (https://github.com/estnltk/estnltk).

An archive contains sentence files with an extension ".gaps" and candidate files with an extension "*.var". Sentence file contains one sentence per line. A line starts with an integer which indicates gap-word's offset in a sentence. The position of the first word in the sentence is zero. Based on the frequency of a gap-word, we generated four kinds of sentence files:

File name             Gap-word frequency
--------------------------------------------------------------
test.all.gaps          any frequency
test.freq.gaps        frequent word form
test.inf_freq.gaps   infrequent word form, frequent word type (lemma)
test.inf_inf.gaps     infrequent word form, infrequent word type (lemma)

To each sentence file relate multiple candidate files. In a candidate file, each line contains a list of 200 candidate words, which correspond to a sentence at the same line in the related sentence file.
Candidate files were generated using the same frequency ranges as sentence files. We also provide four kinds of candidate files:

File suffix        Explanation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
*.pos.var        candidates with the same part of speech as a gap-word
*.syn.var        candidates generated with a morphological generator based on the base form of a gap-word
*.w2v.var       candidate words from word2vec's most similar query
*.random.var  random words
</dc:description>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
