<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:lindat.mff.cuni.cz:11372/LRT-198</identifier>
    <datestamp>2016-04-06T16:39:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hdl_11858_00-097C-0000-0007-710A-A</setSpec>
    <setSpec>hdl_11858_00-097C-0000-0007-710B-8</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>ABC - Language Identifier</dc:title>
      <dc:contributor>Tufi&#351;, Dan</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Ceau&#351;u, Alexandru</dc:contributor>
      <dc:description>The application, developed in C#, automatically identifies the language of a text written in one of the 21 European Union languages. By using training texts in different languages (approx. 1.5Mb of text for each language), a training module counts the prefixes (the first 3 characters) and the suffixes (4 characters endings) for all the words in the texts, for each language. For every language two models are constructed, containing the weights (percentages) of prefixes and suffixes in the texts representing a language. In the prediction phase, for a new text, two models are built on the fly in a similar manner. These models are then compared with the stored models representing each language for which the application was trained. Using comparison functions, the best model is chose. More detailed descriptions are available in [[http://www.racai.ro/~tufis/papers|the following papers]]: -- Dan Tufi&#351;, Radu Ion, Alexandru Ceau&#351;u, and Dan &#350;tef&#259;nescu (2008). RACAI's Linguistic Web Services. In Proceedings of the 6th Language Resources and Evaluation Conference - LREC 2008, Marrakech, Morocco, May 2008. ELRA - European Language Resources Association. ISBN 2-9517408-4-0. -- Dan Tufi&#351; and Alexandru Ceau&#351;u (2007). Diacritics Restoration in Romanian Texts. In Elena Paskaleva and Milena Slavcheva (eds.), A Common Natural Language Processing Paradigm for Balkan Languages - RANLP 2007 Workshop Proceedings, pp. 49-56, Borovets, Bulgaria, September 2007. INCOMA Ltd., Shoumen, Bulgaria. ISBN 978-954-91743-8-0. -- Dan Tufi&#351; and Adrian Chi&#355;u (1999). Automatic Insertion of Diacritics in Romanian Texts. In Ferenc Kiefer, G&#225;bor Kiss, and J&#250;lia Pajzs (eds.), Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Computational Lexicography (COMPLEX 1999), pp. 185-194, Pecs, Hungary, May 1999. Linguistics Institute, Hungarian Academy of Sciences.</dc:description>
      <dc:date>2014-07-30</dc:date>
      <dc:type>toolService</dc:type>
      <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/11372/LRT-198</dc:identifier>
      <dc:format>downloadable_files_count: 0</dc:format>
      <dc:coverage>Romania</dc:coverage>
      <dc:publisher>Research Institute for Artificial Intelligence, Romanian Academy of Sciences</dc:publisher>
      <dc:source>http://www.racai.ro/webservices/</dc:source>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
