<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:repo.clarino.uib.no:11509/103</identifier>
    <datestamp>2016-09-06T12:50:26Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hdl_11509_1</setSpec>
    <setSpec>hdl_11509_2</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>SIKOR Kven free corpus</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Giellatekno - Saami Language Technology, UiT The Arctic University of Norway</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>The Divvun group at UiT The Arctic University of Norway</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject>Monolingual Corpus</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Text Corpus</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Kven Finnish</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>The SIKOR Kven free corpus is a monolingual text corpus of Kven that contains administrative, law, religious, non-fiction, fiction, and news texts. It is work done by the Giellatekno and Divvun research groups, Department of Linguistics, UiT The Arctic University of Norway, as well as by members of the language community. In particular, the following colleagues have contributed to the creation of the ressource: Ciprian Gerstenberger, B&#248;rre Gaup, Sindre Trosterud, Leena Niiranen, Kaisa Maliniemi, Paula Paksuniemi, Mervi Haavisto, Trond Trosterud, and Anne-Kaisa R&#228;is&#228;nen. Linguistically, the data set (21,024 sentences; 182,697 tokens) features word form, lemma, and morphosyntactic analysis. The corpus has been automatically processed and linguistically analyzed with the Giellatekno/Divvun tools. Therefore, it may contain wrong annotations. In case you find any errors the creators would appreciate your feedback sent to giellatekno@uit.no and feedback@divvun.no.&#13;
Please note that the Giellatekno resources are dynamic in nature. To ensure that you have a completely updated version, please contact Giellatekno (see Contact Info in metadata).</dc:description>
      <dc:date>2015-08-03</dc:date>
      <dc:type>corpus</dc:type>
      <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/11509/103</dc:identifier>
      <dc:language>fkv</dc:language>
      <dc:rights>Creative Commons - Attribution 3.0 Unported (CC BY 3.0)</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>CC</dc:rights>
      <dc:format>application/zip</dc:format>
      <dc:format>text/plain; charset=utf-8</dc:format>
      <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
      <dc:format>downloadable_files_count: 1</dc:format>
      <dc:publisher>Giellatekno - Saami Language Technology</dc:publisher>
      <dc:source>http://giellatekno.uit.no/index.eng.html</dc:source>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
