<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:lindat.mff.cuni.cz:11372/LRT-1231</identifier>
    <datestamp>2016-04-06T16:39:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hdl_11858_00-097C-0000-0007-710A-A</setSpec>
    <setSpec>hdl_11858_00-097C-0000-0007-710B-8</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>LXGram</dc:title>
      <dc:contributor>Branco, Ant&#243;nio</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Costa, Francisco</dc:contributor>
      <dc:description>LXGram is a grammar for the computational processing of Portuguese. It is being developed under the following major design features: * precision: it is a precision grammar delivering accurate, linguistically grounded information of natural language sentences * deep processing: it is a grammar for deep linguistic processing in as much as besides information on the major syntactic dimensions of grammatical constituency and dependency, it delivers (and generates from) fully-fledged logical representation of the meaning of natural language sentences * large-scale: it is planned not to leave out any sort of regular grammatical construction or phenomena. * multi-purpose: it is intended to make available as much linguistic information as it can possible be made explicit by automatic means, given the current state of the art in language technology, with the goal of offering itself to support the largest possible range of language technology applications.</dc:description>
      <dc:date>2014-07-30</dc:date>
      <dc:type>toolService</dc:type>
      <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/11372/LRT-1231</dc:identifier>
      <dc:language>por</dc:language>
      <dc:format>downloadable_files_count: 0</dc:format>
      <dc:coverage>Portugal</dc:coverage>
      <dc:publisher>NLX-Natural Language and Speech Group, University of Lisbon</dc:publisher>
      <dc:source>http://nlxgroup.di.fc.ul.pt/lxgram/</dc:source>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
