<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>ffc1c2b0357f11e2a2aa782bcb074135a0708b33105c49d4b11cab77c30d5c75</identifier>
    <datestamp>2018-11-15T16:39:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>toolService</setSpec>
    <setSpec>toolService:tool</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:info="http://www.ilsp.gr/META-XMLSchema" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/          http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>LX-Tokenizer</dc:title>
      <dc:description>The present tool, that was built to deal with Portuguese-specific issues concerning a few non-trivial cases that involve tokenization-ambigous strings, segments text into lexically relevant tokens, using whitespace as the separator. Note that, in these examples, the | (vertical bar) symbol is used to mark the token boundaries clearier:
	
	um exemplo &#226;&#134;&#146; |um|exemplo|

Expands contractions. Note that the first element of an expanded contraction is marked with an _ (underscore) symbol:

	do &#226;&#134;&#146; |de_|o|

Marks spacing around punctuation or symbols. The \* and the */ symbols indicate a space to the left and a space to the right, respectively:

um, dois e tr&#195;&#170;s &#226;&#134;&#146; |um|,*/|dois|e|tr&#195;&#170;s|
 5.3 &#226;&#134;&#146; |5|.|3|
 1. 2 &#226;&#134;&#146; |1|.*/|2|
 8 . 6 &#226;&#134;&#146; |8|\*.*/|6|

Detaches clitic pronouns from the verb. The detached pronoun is marked with a - (hyphen) symbol. When in mesoclisis, a -CL- mark is used to signal the original position of the detached clitic. Additionally, possible vocalic alterations of the verb form are marked with a # (hash) symbol:

	d&#195;&#161;-se-lho &#226;&#134;&#146; |d&#195;&#161;|-se|-lhe|-o|
	afirmar-se-ia &#226;&#134;&#146; |afirmar-CL-ia|-se|
	v&#195;&#170;-las &#226;&#134;&#146; |v&#195;&#170;#|-las|

This tool also handles ambiguous strings. These are words that, depending on their particular occurrence, can be tokenized in different ways. For instance:

deste &#226;&#134;&#146; |deste| when occurring as a Verb
deste &#226;&#134;&#146; |de|este| when occurring as a contraction (Preposition + Demonstrative)
This tool achieves a f-score of 99.72%.

LX-Tokenizer was developed and is maintained at University of Lisbon by the NLX-Natural Language and Speech Group of the Department of Informatics.
</dc:description>
      <dc:date>2012-11-23</dc:date>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
