<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:fedora.clarin-d.uni-saarland.de:clarind-uds:mcscript</identifier>
    <datestamp>2018-07-10T13:05:37Z</datestamp>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>McScript: A Novel Dataset for Assessing Machine Comprehension Using Script Knowledge</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Simon Ostermann, Fachrichtung Sprachwissenschaft und Sprachtechnologie, Universit&#228;t des Saarlandes, Campus C7.4, 66123 Saarbr&#252;cken</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject>Scripts</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Script Knowledge</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Narrative Texts</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Commonsense Knowledge</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Crowdsourcing</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en">The MCScript corpus is a large dataset of narrative texts and questions about these texts, intended to be used in a machine comprehension task that requires reasoning using 
commonsense knowledge. Our dataset complements similar datasets in that we focus on 
stories about everyday activities, such as going to the movies or working in the garden, and 
that the questions require commonsense knowledge, or more specifically, script knowledge, 
to be answered. We show that our mode of data collection via crowdsourcing results in a 
substantial amount of such inference questions. The dataset forms the basis of a shared task 
on commonsense and script knowledge organized at SemEval 2018 and provides 
challenging test cases for the broader natural language understanding community.</dc:description>
      <dc:contributor>Simon Ostermann</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Ashutosh Modi</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Michael Roth</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Stefan Thater</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Manfred Pinkal</dc:contributor>
      <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
      <dc:type>Collection</dc:type>
      <dc:type>Dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>clarind-uds:mcscript</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>hdl:21.11119/0000-0001-D3A7-4</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier/>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>Simon Ostermann, Ashutosh Modi, Michael Roth, Stefan Thater and Manfred Pinkal (2018): "MCScript: A Novel Dataset for Assessing Machine Comprehension Using Script Knowledge". In Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, Miyazaki, Japan. http://www.lrec-conf.org/proceedings/lrec2018/pdf/225.pdf</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights>CC-BY-SA-NC-4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
