<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:lindat.mff.cuni.cz:11372/LRT-1224</identifier>
    <datestamp>2016-04-06T16:39:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hdl_11858_00-097C-0000-0007-710A-A</setSpec>
    <setSpec>hdl_11858_00-097C-0000-0007-710B-8</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>LX-Inflector</dc:title>
      <dc:contributor>Branco, Ant&#243;nio</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Martins, Pedro</dc:contributor>
      <dc:description>Fully fledged automatic nominal lemmatizer for Portuguese. It takes as input: * A Portuguese nominal form A forms of a noun or an adjective, including adjectival forms of past participles, and * Inflectional feature values Intended values of inflectional features of Gender and Number for the output. It delivers: * Inflectional features The input form is returned with the corresponding values for the inflectional features of Gender and Number associated to it; * Lemmata The lemmata (singular and masculine forms when available) possibly corresponding to the input form; * Inflected forms The inflected forms (when available) of each lemmata in accordance with the values for inflectional features entered. LX-Inflector processes simple forms, both lexically known and unknown ones. It also processes compound forms. It handles nominal forms with prefixes as well. In sum, it lemmatizes and inflects: * Prefixed forms Nominal expressions integrating one or more prefixes, e.g. "anti-constitucional", "super-mega-fixe", etc; * Compounds Nominal expressions integrating more than one form, e.g. "trabalhador-estudante", "surdo-mudo", "lan&#231;a-m&#237;sseis", etc; * Neologisms</dc:description>
      <dc:date>2014-07-30</dc:date>
      <dc:type>toolService</dc:type>
      <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/11372/LRT-1224</dc:identifier>
      <dc:language>por</dc:language>
      <dc:format>downloadable_files_count: 0</dc:format>
      <dc:coverage>Portugal</dc:coverage>
      <dc:publisher>NLX-Natural Language and Speech Group, University of Lisbon</dc:publisher>
      <dc:source>http://lxinflector.di.fc.ul.pt</dc:source>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
