<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:fedora.clarin-d.uni-saarland.de:clarind-uds:anvil</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-06-03T12:53:03Z</datestamp>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>Anvil The video annotation research tool</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Michael Kipp
Hochschule Augsburg
An der Hochschule 1
86161 Augsburg
michael.kipp@hs-augsburg.de</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">gesture research</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">video annotation</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">time-alignment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">multimodal corpora</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">phonology</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en">ANVIL is a free video annotation tool. It offers multi-layered annotation based on a user-defined coding scheme. During coding the user can see color-coded elements on multiple tracks in time-alignment. Some special features are cross-level links, non-temporal objects, timepoint tracks, coding agreement analysis and a project tool for managing whole corpora of annotation files.</dc:description>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de">ANVIL ist ein frei erh&#228;ltiches Annotationstool. Es bietet die M&#246;glichkeit zur mehrdimensionalen Annotation basierend auf einem benutzerdefinierten Kodierungsschema. W&#228;hrend des Kodierens sieht der Benutzer farbkodierte Elemente zeitlich alineiert auf mehreren Spuren. Spezielle Features des Werkzeugs sind ebenen&#252;bergreifende Links, nicht-temporale Objekte, Zeitspuren, Analyse der &#220;bereinstimmung der Kodierung und ein Projektwerkzeug f&#252;r die Verwaltung von Annotationsdateien ganzer Korpora.</dc:description>
      <dc:contributor>Michael Kipp</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Quan Nguyen</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Gabriel Manolache</dc:contributor>
      <dc:type>Software</dc:type>
      <dc:identifier>clarind-uds:anvil</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>hdl:11858/00-246C-0000-0005-BD0D-2</dc:identifier>
      <dc:relation>Kipp, M. (to appear) Multimedia Annotation, Querying and Analysis in ANVIL. In: M. Maybury (ed.) Multimedia Information Extraction, Chapter 19, IEEE Computer Society Press.</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>Kipp, M. (to appear) ANVIL: A Universal Video Research Tool. In: J. Durand, U. Gut, G. Kristofferson (Hrsg.) Handbook of Corpus Phonology, Oxford University Press.</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>Heloir, A., Neff, M. and Kipp, M. (2010) Exploiting Motion Capture for Virtual Human Animation: Data Collection and Annotation Visualization. In: Proc. of the LREC Workshop on "Multimodal Corpora: Advances in Capturing, Coding and Analyzing Multimodality", ELDA.</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>Kipp, M. (2008) Spatiotemporal Coding in ANVIL. Proceedings of the 6th international conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC-08).</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>Kipp, M. (2004), Gesture Generation by Imitation - From Human Behavior to Computer Character Animation, Boca Raton, Florida: Dissertation.com. (My published PhD thesis.)</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>Kipp, M. (2001) Anvil - A Generic Annotation Tool for Multimodal Dialogue. Proceedings of the 7th European Conference on Speech Communication and Technology (Eurospeech), pp. 1367-1370.</dc:relation>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
