<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:fedora.clarin-d.uni-saarland.de:clarind-uds:croco</identifier>
    <datestamp>2018-02-01T15:24:37Z</datestamp>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>CroCo</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Universit&#228;t des Saarlandes Fachrichtung 4.6 Englische Sprach- und &#220;bersetzungswissenschaft</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">corpus linguistics</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">linguistics</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">translation</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en">explicitation</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en">The CroCo corpus is a bidirectional corpus of German (GO) and English (EO) texts from 8 registers (popular-scientific texts, tourism leaflets, prepared speeches, political essays on economics, fictional texts, corporate communication, instruction manuals, websites) with the respective English (ETrans) and German (GTrans) translation.
Thus we have: multilingual comparable subcorpora (EO and GO, ETrans and GTrans), monolingual comparable subcorpora (EO and ETrans, GO and GTrans) and parallel subcorpora (EO and GTrans, GO and ETrans).
The corpus is annotated with lemma, POS, morphological information, phrasal chunks and grammatical functions. The parallel corpora are aligned on different levels: word, chunk, clause and sentence.</dc:description>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de">Das CroCo-Korpus ist ein bidirektionales Korpus bestehend aus deutschen (GO) und englischen (EO) Texten aus 8 Registern (popul&#228;rwissenschaftliche Texte, Tourismus-Flyer, Reden, politische Essays &#252;ber Wirtschaft, fiktionale Texte, Firmenkommunikation, Handb&#252;cher, Webseiten) mit den jeweiligen Englischen (ETrans) und Deutschen (GTrans) &#220;bersetzungen.
Demnach gibt es multilinguale vergleichbare Subkorpora (EO und GO, ETrans und GTrans), monolinguale vergleichbare Subkorpora (EO und ETrans, GO und GTrans) und parallele Subkorpora (EO und GTrans, GO und ETrans).
Das Korpus ist mit Lemma, POS, morphologischer Information, phrasalen Chunks und grammatischen Funktionen annotiert. Die parallelen Subkorpora sind auf verschiedenen Ebenen alligniert: Wort, Chunk, Clause, Satz.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher>Universit&#228;t des Saarlandes</dc:publisher>
      <dc:contributor>Oliver &#268;ulo</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Silvia Hansen-Schirra</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Kerstin Kunz</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Stella Neumann</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Prof. Erich Steiner</dc:contributor>
      <dc:contributor>Mihaela Vela</dc:contributor>
      <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
      <dc:type>Collection</dc:type>
      <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>clarind-uds:croco</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>hdl:11858/00-246C-0000-0005-BD0E-F</dc:identifier>
      <dc:language>deu</dc:language>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Hansen-Schirra, Silvia, Neumann, Stella and Steiner, Erich. 2012. Cross-linguistic Corpora for the Study of Translations. Insights from the language pair English -- German. Series Text, Translation, Computational Processing. Berlin, New York: Mouton de Gruyter</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">CroCo-Meta is an user-friendly annotation tool to edit and storage meta information for a file header. http://fedora.clarin-d.uni-saarland.de/croco-gecco/croco/CroCoMeta_en.html</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Deliverable No. 1 "Corpus Design": http://hdl.handle.net/21.11119/0000-0000-8138-F</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Deliverable No. 2 "Encoding of Metainformation": http://hdl.handle.net/21.11119/0000-0000-8148-D</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Deliverable No. 3 "Multidimensional Corpus Alignment": http://hdl.handle.net/21.11119/0000-0000-814E-7</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Deliverable No. 4 "Categories for the Annotation": http://hdl.handle.net/21.11119/0000-0000-8159-A</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Deliverable No. 5 "Types of contrasts, linguistic levels, their relationship to explicitation and explicitness, and possible explanations": http://hdl.handle.net/21.11119/0000-0000-815F-4</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation xml:lang="en">Publications: http://fedora.clarin-d.uni-saarland.de/croco-gecco/croco/publication_en.html</dc:relation>
      <dc:coverage xml:lang="en">Germany</dc:coverage>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyrighted</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
