<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>12832_fgdc</identifier>
    <datestamp>2017-09-14T02:58:33Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>PDCMetadata</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <metadata>
      <idinfo>
        <citation>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Chen, Wenjun</origin>
            <origin>Hossain, M. Faruque</origin>
            <origin>Zhang, Yu</origin>
            <pubdate>20170913</pubdate>
            <title>A database for soil organic carbon in northern Canada</title>
            <geoform>Computer file</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>unknown</pubplace>
              <publish>Data Citation: Hossain, F. M., Chen, W. and Zhang, Y. (2017) A database for soil organic carbon in northern Canada. Waterloo, Canada: Canadian Cryospheric Information Network (CCIN). Unpublished Data
Additional Publication- can be accessed: Hossain, M. F., Zhang, Y., Chen, W., Wang, J. and Pavlic, G. 2007. Soil organic carbon content in northern Canada: A database of field measurements and its analysis. Can. J. Soil Sci. 87: 259&#8211;268. doi: 10.4141/S06-029</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>unavailable</othercit>
            <onlink>https://www.polardata.ca/pdcsearch/PDCSearchDOI.jsp?doi_id=12832</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
          <abstract>Available field measurements of soil organic carbon (SOC) in northern Canada were compiled and a database was developed by checking related papers and reports as well as through personal contacts. Additionally, to provide more information on areas where data was missing, studies were conducted in Yellowknife, Northwest Territories and in the Lupin gold mining area, Nunavut in 2005. Including our recent measurements, the database contains 438 profiles with 1473 soil horizons. Preliminary analysis shows that the SOC content of subsurface soils is relatively high in northern regions. In the top 100 cm of soils, 40% of the SOC is located in the 50 to 100 cm layer. The SOC content is lower in northern Arctic and in mountainous regions. The average upland SOC content in northern Canada is higher than in other world biomes (i.e. croplands, temperate forest, tropical savannahs, and tropical forest) except temperate grasslands and boreal forest.</abstract>
          <purpose>Arctic and Sub-Arctic soils contain a large amount of organic carbon in their topsoil horizons and in the upper layers of permafrost. There is concern that climate warming could release this soil organic carbon (SOC) to the atmosphere as greenhouse gases. However, information about the profile features of the soil (SOC concentrations based on horizons and depths) and spatial distribution of SOC in northern ecosystems are far less than for other regions. This study compiled available field measurements of SOC in northern Canada. This project is funded by 1) a joint program between Environment Canada and Natural Resources Canada for estimation of greenhouse gases emissions and removals from land use changes over Canada&#8217;s arctic and sub-arctic; 2) Climate Change Geoscience Program (CCGP), Natural Resources Canada; 3) Canadian Space Agency&#8217;s Government Related Initiatives Program (GRIP); and 4) Polar Knowledge Canada Science and Technology (POLAR S&amp;amp;T) program.</purpose>
          <supplinf>Summary: Not Applicable Research Program(s): Other,POLAR/CHARS. For further information: yu.zhang@canada.ca</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19530101</begdate>
              <enddate>99991231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <current>NULL</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
          <progress>In work</progress>
          <update>Irregular</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-141</westbc>
            <eastbc>-61</eastbc>
            <northbc>82</northbc>
            <southbc>60</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
          <theme>
            <themekt>NULL</themekt>
            <themekey>Arctic</themekey>
            <themekey>Database</themekey>
            <themekey>Greenhouse gas</themekey>
            <themekey>Northern Canada</themekey>
            <themekey>Organic carbon</themekey>
            <themekey>Permafrost</themekey>
            <themekey>Subarctic</themekey>
          </theme>
          <place>
            <placekt>Northern Canada&#8194;(above 60 degrees north)</placekt>
            <placekey>NULL</placekey>
          </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Public</accconst>
        <useconst>NULL</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Natural Resources Canada</cntorg>
              <cntper>Yu Zhang</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>NULL</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
              <address>560 Rochester Street</address>
              <city>Ottawa</city>
              <state>Ontario</state>
              <postal>K1A 0E4</postal>
              <country>Canada</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(613)759-6024</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(613)759-6344</cntfax>
            <cntemail>yu.zhang@canada.ca</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>NULL</datacred>
      </idinfo>
      <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Polar Data Catalogue</cntper>
              <cntorg>Canadian Cryospheric Information Network</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Director</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
              <address>200 University Avenue West, University of Waterloo</address>
              <city>Waterloo</city>
              <state>Ontario</state>
              <postal>N2L 3G1</postal>
              <country>Canada</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(519) 888-4567 x32689</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(519) 888-6768</cntfax>
            <cntemail>pdc@uwaterloo.ca</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <resdesc>12832</resdesc>
        <distliab>Research programs, CCIN, or ArcticNet take no liability for the use or transmission of this data</distliab>
      </distinfo>
      <metainfo>
        <metd>20170615</metd>
        <metrd>20170913</metrd>
        <metc>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Yu Zhang</cntper>
              <cntorg>Natural Resources Canada</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
              <address>560 Rochester Street</address>
              <city>Ottawa</city>
              <state>Ontario</state>
              <postal>K1A 0E4</postal>
              <country>Canada</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(613)759-6024</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(613)759-6344</cntfax>
            <cntemail>yu.zhang@canada.ca</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      </metainfo>
    </metadata>
  </metadata>
</record>
