<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:datarep.app.ist.ac.at:66</identifier>
    <datestamp>2017-04-12T08:05:45Z</datestamp>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>Light Sheet Fluorescence microscopy of plant roots growing on the surface of a gel</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>von Wangenheim, Daniel</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hauschild, Robert</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Friml, Ji&#345;&#237; </dc:creator>
      <dc:subject>580 Plants</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>One of the key questions in understanding plant development is how single cells behave in a larger context of the tissue. Therefore, it requires the observation of the whole organ with a high spatial- as well as temporal resolution over prolonged periods of time, which may cause photo-toxic effects. This protocol shows a plant sample preparation method for light-sheet microscopy, which is characterized by mounting the plant vertically on the surface of a gel. The plant is mounted in such a way that the roots are submerged in a liquid medium while the leaves remain in the air. In order to ensure photosynthetic activity of the plant, a custom-made lighting system illuminates the leaves. To keep the roots in darkness the water surface is covered with sheets of black plastic foil. This method allows long-term imaging of plant organ development in standardized conditions. &#13;
The Video is licensed under a CC BY NC ND license. </dc:description>
      <dc:type>Data Collection</dc:type>
      <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
      <dc:format>video</dc:format>
      <dc:relation>https://datarep.app.ist.ac.at/66/</dc:relation>
      <dc:identifier>https://datarep.app.ist.ac.at/66/1/WangenheimHighResolution55044-NEW_1.mp4</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>  von Wangenheim, Daniel and Hauschild, Robert and Friml, Ji&#345;&#237;    Light Sheet Fluorescence microscopy of plant roots growing on the surface of a gel.  [Data Collection]     </dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.15479/AT:ISTA:66</dc:identifier>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
